Jerry Ryle

I am an engineering leader with a strong software engineering background and a breadth of experience in product development. I build and manage teams that solve challenging engineering problems with a user-centric approach. I work closely with finance, operations, sales, and marketing to ensure that we meet our business objectives while we ship products that people love.

Experience

Alpine Health, Mountain View, CA **V.P. Engineering**, 2017-2018

- · Hired and led a cross-functional team of engineers and consultants to build a revolutionary consumer health device
- Produced our key patent application
- Bootstrapped the company: set up payroll and benefits, hired development partners, created our interview process, defined our peer review and feedback process, codified our development methodology, and made coffee

Mindtribe Product Engineering, San Francisco, CA Partner and V.P. Engineering, 2001-2017

- As a partner and vice president, I was responsible for business development, sales, program management, process development, strategy, hiring, and mentorship
- Built Mindtribe into a 40-person, world-class engineering consultancy
- Brought Agile values to hardware engineering, enabling rapid product development
- Was the primary thought leader for improving our engineering methodology
- Scaled numerous startups from MVP to mass-market

Key Mindtribe projects that I managed (many more on my portfolio site at jerryryle.com):

Stealth Company, Encrypted Communications Device, 2015-2016

- Led a cross-functional team to take a complex, consumer electronics device for encrypted voice communications from concept through manufacturing in less than a year
- Took over management of two engineering teams, an electrical consultant, an audio consultant, an app development firm, a security auditor, and a contract manufacturer in the Philippines
- Solved technical challenges relating to security, testability, and manufacturability

Adobe, Project Parallel, 2012

- Led a team of developers and designers to create Line, Adobe's Ink and Slide showcase app
- Taught the rapid development methodology that we used on Line to Adobe's other app teams

Square, Stand, 2012

- Led a cross-functional team of engineers to deliver Stand, Square's point-of sale solution for brick-and-mortar retailers
- Structured and ran this program from concept through manufacturing
- Set clear priorities for the team, which allowed us go from concept to shipping product in less than a year

Education

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA | B.S., Computer Engineering, Class of 2000

Patents

 $US20190000599A1 \; (pending) \; \hbox{--} \; Systems \; and \; methods \; for \; personalized \; or al \; irrigation \; \label{eq:pending}$

US9262777B2 - Card reader with power efficient architecture that includes a wake-up circuit

US9286635B2 - Method of transmitting information from efficient communication protocol card readers to mobile devices

US9495676B2 - Method of transmitting information from a power efficient card to a mobile device

WO2012177370A1 - Wireless input device